Hello, all of you are very welcome
to Sadhna News and I am Manish Kumar with you.
Serious allegations have been made against a well-known insurance company.  It
is alleged that ICICI LBAD General
Insurance Company rejected the claim of a four-wheeler worth ₹33 lakh
after the accident without any
concrete reasons.  Now the affected
customers are forced to wander from door to door.
In such a situation, the question is that when the premium was
paid on time and in full, then
why did the insurance company give up in times of trouble?   Is
n't this cheating the customers?  This
is the biggest question.  Watch this special report.
Be careful while choosing a vehicle insurance company.
Otherwise, you will have to spend a lot of money on insurance for the accident-hit vehicle.
ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company
defrauded the customer.
Four wheeler vehicle claim worth Rs 33 lakh.
Rejected even after the accident.
Even after paying the full premium, the company
rejected the insurance claim.  The
company's arbitrariness even after showing evidence related to the accident.  The
case is related to a luxury car worth ₹33 lakh.
Which was insured with ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company.
A few days ago the car met with a road accident.  The
vehicle suffered heavy damage in the accident.  The
customer
completed all the formalities and filed a claim with the insurance company.
But the company rejected the claim after investigation.
I paid a premium of more than Rs.
When I submitted all the
papers that ICICI LB company
asked for for the insurance of the car, I
submitted them one by one and then when
I sent the papers to them for our claim,
I got a call from there that sir your claim has been
rejected.  Now tell me that I
paid more than ₹1 lakh premium to them.
Gave all the papers to him.  Now where is my mistake
?  Please take this matter into consideration.   The
insurance company says that the claim is
not valid as per the terms of the policy.  But the
customer alleges that no concrete and
clear reason was given to him.  The victim
says that despite providing the survey report and
all the evidence related to the accident, the company
rejected the claim on technical grounds.
If they ask for anything more as per such documentation,
we are still ready to provide it.
But for our claim
they called and said that your claim has been rejected,
please provide me any legal help for that.  We tried to
contact IC ICI Lombard on this matter.
But till the time of writing this news, no
official response has come from the company.
This case is not only a
story of one customer's trouble but
also raises questions for thousands of people
who take insurance with trust.
I took insurance from ICICI Lo LBAT company
and they rejected my insurance claim.
Now people should be careful of such bad companies.
Customers should become aware
so that people keep distance from such companies.
My experience as a lawyer is
that the client ultimately has to approach the court to get his claim.
When any
kind of trouble comes to him, the insurance
company
rejects his claim by giving some excuse or the other.
So finally this is my experience of ICICI LBA.
I've been having a
lot of episodes of that.  When the claim
of any customer goes above Rs 5-10 lakh, then ICICI LB
rejects his claim by making any excuse and
finally we have to go to the consumer forum and
fight for that claim after a long battle to
get it.
So the customer first pays a hefty premium
to the insurance company and
his motive behind that hefty premium is
that when he faces trouble, the
insurance company should help him but the
insurance company does not help, in this
only the court of law helps him.
I have told this about my experience.  I have
seen from my experience that a person gets justice only by taking recourse to the court.
Insurance companies
back off whenever a customer faces such a problem.  Out of which,
I have recently seen many cases of ICICI LBD in which they
withdrew their hands from whatever claims the customers had.  At some places, they
call it over speeding and they have
a ground for it for which there is no evidence.
They just have to write that it was done due to over
speeding.
Till date, no company has been able to present any evidence of over speeding
in any court.
But by writing over speeding, it rejects the customer's
claim in 90% of the cases.
Now it remains to be seen whether the victim gets justice
or not and whether the insurance company clarifies its stand on this.
Bureau Report, Sadhna
News.